

Viacheslav Gusev

тел. +7 (926) 530-94-25 email: sono@gusevv.ru

Telegram: https://t.me/ViacheslavGusev
portfolio: https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev

Data Scientist

Key competencies

- Collecting and analyzing customer requirements for the product;
- Understanding key metrics for business, meaningful interpretation of KPIs;
- Application of key mathematical methods and fundamentals of statistics in the work;
- Data analysis in Excel (pivot tables, OLAP, Power Query, DAX formulas, data visualization);
- o Building interactive dashboards in Power BI, Looker Studio (GDS), Tableau, Data Lens;
- I know SQL syntax, I can make queries to PostgreSQL databases (CTE, views, window functions, subqueries, joins);
- o I can develop applications in Python, I know the basics of object-oriented programming;
- I have an idea about the integration of GPT models into neuropromeshnik development projects;
- I own libraries for data analysis and machine learning: Pandas, NumPy,MPL, Scipy, Statistics, Pyspark,
 Sklearn XGBoost, CatBoost, LightGBM;
- I work with classical ML algorithms, I can work with features, outlier search, Feature Engineering, Feature
 Selection, build ML models to solve regression, classification and clustering problems;
- I have experience in using advanced ML models based on gradient boosting, decision trees, ensembling, stacking;
- I can work with DL: train neural networks from scratch, adapt pre-trained models to specific tasks, perform Fine-Tuning (Tensorflou, Keras, PyTorch)
- He solved practical problems in Object Detection, OCR-HKR
- Understanding RecSys (item-base, user-base, hybrid approaches)
- o I am familiar with the analysis and forecast of time series;
- o Linux at the user level, Bash, Git
- The Scrum approach.

Professional experience

01.2024 - present time

Data Scientist

Synergy Soft, Developer of IT solutions for the public and corporate sector, part of Synergy Corporation, Moscow

www.synergy.ru

Department of Digital Transformation of Synergy University:

- Development of a chatbot with integration via the Yandex OCR API. More information about the implementation of the project: https://habr.com/ru/articles/815727 / Framework: Pandas, OpenCV, Request, Aiogram, Open AI;
- Development of neural networks Object Detection and Transformer-HTR for recognizing fields of handwritten questionnaires. Fine-tuning of models. Framework: Pandas, OpenCV, Pwtorch; Link to the party portfolio: https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev/HTR_Questionnaries
- formation of requirements for data collection and creation of representations in DWH for the university student outflow project;
- formation of a training dataset, EDA, hypotheses for solving the outflow problem;
- building ML classification models to solve the outflow problem. Evaluation of metrics, description of requirements for enriching training data to improve the quality of the model. Framework: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Sklearn, XGBoost, LightGBM, CatBoost Decision Tree;

- Participation in the HR analytics project: description of the requirements for collecting data on department employees for predictive analytics of satisfaction and outflow risk, development of a database architecture for the employee survey site, formation of an ETL task for the DWH data collection process, building a prototype interactive dashboard based on the results of the employee survey;
- Scrum master in the AI development and implementation teams and the project office of the Digital Transformation Department: holding action meetings, retrospectives, planning sprints. Facilitation, motivation, formation of self-organizing teams;
- Implementation of Jira. Creating workspaces, forming the logic of work in the program, building Agile tools (Scrum and Canban boards).

10.2022 - 01.2024

Lead Product Manager

Komus, Moscow

www.komus.org

- Management of the product line development strategy (2400 SKU, 6 Product Categories), Competitive analysis, definition of the category development vector, medium- and long-term planning, data visualization to protect the strategy in front of the Company's Top management;
- Development and implementation of an interactive product category management dashboard based on OLAP cubes for the assortment management group;

Link to the portfolio: https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev/Commodity_Analytics_EXCEL

- Development of a report template with visualization to prepare for the review category; Link to the portfolio: https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev/Category Review
- Sending ABC-XYZ analysis of Python environments based on the specifications of this company. Report processing, data consolidation, conclusions, determination of actions to optimize the Product Matrix:

Link to the portfolio: https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev/ABC XYZ Classification

- Development of an algorithm for determining positions suitable for setting up minimum batches and marketing packages. Analysis of project results;
- Link to the portfolio: https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev/Min_batch/blob/main/MinBatch.ipynb
- development of a Python script for generating reports and calculating employee motivation through sales channels;
- participation in the dynamic pricing project, setting up a pricing strategy to increase profitability for assortment baskets (KVI, turnover maker, traffic maker, long tail), forming requirements for tagging positions by product categories;
- Identification of key characteristics of product items, setting up classification and search filters in the online store;
- Interaction with suppliers:
- Commodity movement management;
- Working with sales tools, training.

11.2003 - 10.2022

Head of Departments and Departments

Russian and Italian companies

www.ital-on.ru www.union.ru www.effebiquattro.it www.italserramenti.it www.scrigno.net www.wwts.ru www.barausse.it www.belfan.ru www.olimp-parketa.ru www.artishock.ru

Main functions:

- Procurement management, budgeting, supplier search, key negotiations with LPR, optimization of conditions, development of relations
- Marketing research of consumer demand, definition of the assortment matrix, introduction of new products to the
- Product analytics, Assortment matrix management: ABC, XYZ analysis, evaluation and work with efficiency, optimization of turnover, increase in marginality
- Pricing, profitability management, product promotion strategy to the market. Identification of the main sales channels
- Development and implementation of KPI and motivation system for assortment management and sales department

- -Organization and participation in international and regional exhibitions
- Product and technology trainings for sales departments and partners. Assessment of knowledge and certification. Technical support for sales

Progress:

- He went from procurement, product analytics, assortment management to director of assortment management
- Formation of management and efficiency skills. MBA practice in self-study mode
- --Increase the marginality of the company's products by 15% due to the change of strategic suppliers
- Increase in sales in the direction by 30% during the year
- Participation and successful implementation of contract projects in Armenia, Azerbaijan, Russia

Education

2001 Moscow Aviation Institute (National Research University), Moscow

"Rocket Engineering", Aerospace Faculty, Design Engineer

Courses, trainings:

2024 Netology, Data Scientist

2020 MBA in practice, Self-education in topics, Procurement, Assortment Management, Marketing, SMM,

Sales Management, Business Management, Financial planning

2018 Pro retail, Operational management of retail sales

2004 Intensive Foreign language courses, Italian language

Additional information:

Foreign language: English B1, Italian C2 Readiness for business trips or relocation.

About me

For 20 years, I have gained experience in analyzing and optimizing purchases and assortment matrices, and managing teams.

My desire to explore and learn new things led me to the Data Scientist Netology course from scratch to middle, which I successfully completed.

The stack that I currently have and use in practice:

Excel pivot tables, OLAP, Power Query, DAX formulas, data visualization

Power BI, Looker Studio (GDS), Tableau, Data Lens;

PostgreSQL (CTE, views, window functions, subqueries, joins);

Python (Pandas, NumPy, MPL, Scipy, Statistics, Pyspark);

ML (Sklearn, XGBoost, CatBoost, LightGBM, Decision Tree, ensembling, stacking, boosting),

Deep Learning (Tensorflou, Keras, PyTorch)

Portfolio:

https://github.com/VyacheslavGusev

My rich professional experience in the field of team management and motivation allows me to effectively put Scrum and Agile approaches into practice, lead development teams and project teams as a Scrum master, and jointly achieve significant results in a short time.

I don't drink smoothies, I play hockey, I go skiing